[roars]
[narrator] Strange beasts
and monsters...
vast riches, hidden treasures...
evil haunts, uncharted frontiers...
the mysterious unknown.
The people who are captivated
by the magic in those words...
are called...
Hunters.
[theme song plays]
So...
I'll make sure all three of you
get safely dropped off
at the port closest to the exam site.
How does that sound?
All right!
TEST x OF x TESTS
DOLLE HARBOR
[narrator]
After winning over the old captain,
Gon, Kurapika and Leorio
arrived at Dolle Harbor,
where their adventures
were just beginning.
Thanks a lot, Captain.
That was really fun.
[laughs] I've got to admit,
I had a pretty good time, myself.
Oh, yeah, let me give you a bit of advice
as a small token of my appreciation.
Advice, sir?
Look. Do you see that big cedar tree?
The one up on the top of that hill?
[Gon] Uh-huh.
[Captain]
You'll wanna make your way there first.
It's a shortcut to the exam site.
[Gon] A shortcut? Great!
So, just head for that tree, huh?
Thanks for the tip, Captain.
You're the best.
Good luck to you.
Thanks! Have a safe trip!
Take care of yourself!
[Captain] You can rest easy, Ging.
Your boy's grown into a fine young man.
[snickers]
-[Leorio] Hmm, that's odd.
-[Gon] What is?
[Leorio] Well, uh, according
to this notice I received,
the exam is supposed to be held
somewhere in Zaban City, you see?
Now, we're here, and that tree is there,
which is the opposite direction of Zaban.
Could you have misheard the captain?
I don't think so. He told me I should go
towards that cedar tree.
I see.
And this stupid notice isn't any help
at all.
It says the exam's in Zaban City,
but it doesn't say where, exactly!
Our task is to find the site
using only limited information.
This is another test to determine
if we're worthy of the Exam.
Yeah, I already knew that,
smarty pants! So give it a rest!
[Gon] I think I’ll check it out for myself
Find out what the captain
was talking about.
[Leorio] Whoa, whoa. Are you serious?
The bus to Zaban is gonna leave
any second!
We need to be on it when it does.
Hey!
Geez. The kid’s too trusting
for his own good.
You can’t just trust everyone
all the time.
Kurapika, come back!
I’m intrigued by the captain’s advice,
but even more so by Gon’s behavior.
I’m curious to see what he’ll do.
All right, whatever. See ya!
It wasn’t long but it was nice knowing ya.
Another follower,
just like the rest of ‘em.
Not me, though. I’m gonna take the bus.
[man 1] So, it was a trap?
[man 2] All I’m sayin’ is none
of the buses made it to Zaban City.
[man 1 chuckles]
Rookies always fail this part.
They believe whatever you tell ‘em!
[chuckles]
[Leorio] Hey, hey, hey, wait for me!
[Leorio] It’s just I knew you guys
would be lonely without me.
Plus, it’s no fun traveling alone!
That’s why I figured I’d stick with you
two a little while longer. [laughs]
[wind whistling]
[squawks]
[Leorio] Man, this is one creepy place.
There isn’t a single soul anywhere.
No. There’s a bunch of people here!
[gasps] What?
[all gasp]
[Leorio] What’s up with these guys?
Exciting.
"Exciting"?
Time for the exciting
multiple-choice quiz!
[band playing instruments]
[crow caws]
Let me take a guess. You boys are headed
for the cedar on the hill, aren’t you?
There’s only one way to get there.
You’ll have to pass
through this town first.
[all] Huh?
[old lady] You must pass a quiz
comprised of a single question.
Wait a second! What is going on here?
[old lady]
You’ll have five seconds to answer.
If you’re correct, then you can move on.
If not, you’re disqualified
from this year’s Exam.
Oh, I see.
It’s another trial we have to pass
before taking the Exam.
So that’s it, huh?
Lucky I’m an expert in quizzes.
Wait, one question?
Your answer must be
either the number one or two.
Any answer that is not the number one
or number two will be deemed incorrect.
Hold on! All three of us
have to share the same question?
So if Kurapika here gets it wrong,
it means I get disqualified, too?
Not very likely.
Although, if the roles were reversed,
-it would be all but inevitable.
-You wanna repeat that?
It's okay! Even if only one of us
knows the answer,
all three of us get to move on. [chuckles]
And I'm real bad at quizzes.
-True.
-Fair point.
[man] Hey, hey.
Hurry it up, or I might answer it
before the rest of you get a chance.
-[Leorio] So, who the heck are you?
-[Gon] You don’t know?
He’s been following us pretty closely
ever since we left the port.
[Leorio] Really?
Yeah, sorry, kid.
Didn’t mean to eavesdrop, but I couldn’t
help but hear you guys talking.
[old lady] What will you do?
[Leorio] He seems pretty eager to me.
Should we let him go first, guys?
See what kind of question
we can expect from them?
-[Gon] Sure. I'm okay with that.
-[Kurapika] No objections here.
[Matthew] Let's get to it, then.
Once I ace this quiz,
I’m gonna leave a trail of traps
for anyone who tries to follow me.
Now, here is your question.
-[horn tooting]
-[crow caws]
A group of evil villains have kidnapped
your mother and your true love
and you can only save one of them.
Choose one for your mother
or two for your true love.
Which do you save and which of them dies?
-[Gon, Leorio and Kurapika gasp]
-Hey! What kind of quiz is this?
[snickers]
[bell rings]
The answer’s number one.
Oh? And what's your reason?
It’s your mom!
It’s not like you can replace your mom.
But a lover,
you can always find another one.
-What?
-[crow caws]
-You may pass.
-Seriously?
Looks like the trick is telling
the old lady whatever she wants to hear.
Adios!
Hang on! What kind of crap is that?
There's no way that was the right answer!
We’re just supposed to say
what we think she wants to hear?
What's up with that?
-Say something.
-[crow caws]
Ugh, okay.
I’ve had just about enough of this.
-I’m gonna find my own way!
-[old lady] It's too late for that.
Refuse to take the quiz if you wish.
But know you’ll be disqualified.
Grr, that's nuts!
Different people would answer that
in different ways!
There’s no right answer for that question
and never has been.
[gasps] There is no right answer?
-I see.
-Oh?
-Leorio!
-That's enough!
[old lady] The boy with the cat eyes
has figured it out.
I don’t want to hear another word
out of you.
Say anything but your answer
and you’re disqualified.
[Kurapika] You can do this, Leorio.
This is just a simple trick.
Gon...
And now here is your question.
-[horn tooting]
-[crow caws]
You learn both your son and your daughter
have been kidnapped.
You will only be able
to rescue one of them.
Choose one for your son,
and two for your daughter.
Which of these two will you rescue?
[Leorio] Grr! She's messing with us!
[old lady] Five... four...
[Leorio] Go ahead and count down,
you old hag.
...three...
two...
-[Leorio grunts]
-...one!
[mimics buzzer] Time is up!
[yells]
Out of the way, Kurapika!
This old hag needs to be taught a lesson
and I’m gonna make sure she gets it!
Would you please calm down?
How the hell do you expect me
to calm down?
We got it right!
Do you really want to jeopardize that?
We did?
We’ve already given the correct response
Silence. Any other answer
would have been incorrect.
[Leorio] What do you mean, "silence"?
Just that. You said it yourself, remember?
[Leorio] Huh?
There’s no right answer for that question
and never has been!
You were right.
There was no correct answer
to our question.
However, we had to say "one" or "two"
as a response.
And so, our only choice was to respond
with silence.
What about that guy? He made it through!
She never told him he was correct.
All she said was “you may pass.”
Which means that this is not the path
to the Hunter Exam.
Right?
Hmm. That is correct.
The real path is right over here.
Follow this path for two hours
and you will reach the lone cedar tree.
Okay. I was not expecting this.
There is a couple that live
in a small cabin under that tree
who will serve as Navigators
on your journey.
They will guide you to the Exam site,
if you live up to their expectations,
that is.
I’m sorry. I hope you’ll forgive me
for being rude.
Don't be. I don't mind.
Meeting people like you is the only reason
I do this job in the first place.
Do your best. Become the best Hunter
you can be.
[chuckles] Sure.
-[Gon groans]
-[Leorio] Huh?
I'm stuck.
I can't figure out the right answer.
[Leorio chuckles]
You’ve really been thinking of an answer
this whole time? You can stop now.
[Gon] Huh? But why?
[Kurapika]
Because the quiz is already over.
[Gon] I know that,
but what if... you know?
Well, what if that really happens
to me someday?
If two people are in trouble
and I can only help one of them?
Then what?
It wouldn’t be right to pick one
over the other.
But like it or not,
that’s a choice I might have to make.
I just hope that I know what to do.
[old lady] The boy is right, of course.
That is indeed the true purpose
of this test.
The abstract may come to pass
and a Hunter must be ready.
Reality can be cruel, and it often strikes
without warning.
One must always be prepared
for these crossroads in life.
HUNTER GLOSSARY
KURAPIKA
[Leorio] Man, I can’t see a thing
“You’ll reach the top in two hours,”
she said.
Well, it was two hours, two hours ago!
[tuts]
Another “Beware of Magical Beasts” sign?
I’m starting to think we’re never gonna
find this stupid Exam site.
Guys, I'm so hungry!
I need to take a dump!
-[Gon] Try to keep up, Leorio!
-I need to pee too! Hey, guys?
-I think I see it.
-[Gon] Huh?
[knocking on door]
[Leorio] Hey? Anybody home?
I guess not.
[Leorio] Coming in!
[all] Huh?
[beast cackling]
-[Leorio] Magical Beast.
-[Gon] A what?
It appears to be a Kiriko.
It can take on human form!
-They’re extremely intelligent.
-[woman whimpering]
He’s got a woman.
And the guy on the floor looks
like he needs a doctor, bad!
Please help. Save her!
You have to save my wife.
Leorio, see to his injuries!
Right! I'm on it!
[Kurapika] Even in pitch darkness,
he can still see and keep pace
with such a faint shadow.
[Gon grunting]
Impressive.
[Gon] Kiriko, let the lady go!
Why don’t you try to take her from me?
[yelps]
You hear that? It can talk.
That’s amazing!
The Kiriko is a Magical Beast
capable of human speech.
Really? Well, that ought to make this
a lot easier.
-Hey, come here, you dumb Kiriko!
-What?
[Kiriko] This kid's fast.
Kurapika!
[pants] Damn, that was reckless.
Stupid kid! You're gonna pay!
Hey, wait up!
Are you hurt, miss?
Are you feeling pain anywhere at all?
I'm fine, but... what about my husband?
Is he alright?
Not to worry.
Our friend is taking good care of him.
Then please. You have to take me to him,
I beg you!
[Leorio] Huh? Those tattoos...
-Wait, you're not--
-[Leorio] Kurapika.
-Huh?
-You okay?
Leorio.
[Leorio] Guess you are. What a relief.
How is the man you were caring for?
Good! I think he’ll pull through fine.
Lucky for him, the wound wasn’t
as deep as it looked,
I gave him some painkillers
so he’s sleeping it off back at the cabin
I see.
[grunts]
[snickers] How'd you know?
How could you tell that I was an imposter?
[Kurapika] To be honest,
I didn’t actually think you were.
You see, Leorio made a promise
that he’d take care of that injured man.
When I saw him,
I assumed he had left the man all alone.
And with the Magical Beast
still on the loose,
I attacked him for abandoning
his obligation.
Nothing more.
[Kiriko snickers]
[Kurapika] And you, tell me right now.
Who are you and what is it
you want from us?
[Gon] Wait!
[Kiriko cackling]
You're pretty fast for a kid, you know?
You really hit me.
I didn't expect that from you.
That's quite an accomplishment.
Unfortunately for you,
it comes with a higher price
than you bargained for.
Kiri, kiri, kiri, kiri, kiri!
-So, who are you?
-[Kiriko grunts]
You're not the one I was chasing, are you?
The one that I hit?
Um... are you a friend of his?
[Kiriko] Hold on. How can you tell
that I'm not the same one from before?
Huh? Oh, well, you look totally different.
Your voice is different, too.
It's higher and kinda thinner.
[Kiriko chuckles then laughs hysterically]
What's up? Why are you laughing?
Is it something I said?
[Kiriko] Hey! Hey, honey! Come here!
You’re gonna get a kick out of this!
[Kiriko 1 chuckles] How many years
has it been
since anyone was able
to tell the two of us apart?
[Kiriko 2] I'm so happy.
Can you tell ‘em apart? Seriously.
No, not at all.
Don’t you see? The Kiriko that Kurapika
and I hit is actually the husband.
[Leorio and Kurapika]
And which one is that, exactly?
[Kiriko 1]
Allow us to introduce ourselves.
We are the Navigators.
Our family provides support
for the Hunter Exam.
-I'm their daughter.
-I'm their son.
[Leorio]
Man. Great job. You sure had us fooled
The Exam site moves around.
Keeps it interesting.
But that’s exactly why they relocate it
every year. Understand?
They hire Navigators like us to help
by guiding worthy applicants
to the examination site.
Oh, so that how it works?
But don’t get the wrong idea.
We don’t help every candidate.
[son] First, we test them to see if
they’re even qualified to take the Exam.
Make sure they have what it takes.
-[daughter] Mr. Kurapika?
-Yes?
We made certain that we only gave you
the most vague of hints
but you were still able to pick up on them
and determine that we weren’t
actually a married couple.
You only caught a glimpse of my tattoos.
But you knew that in this region,
these tattoos are only worn
by women who’ve taken a vow of chastity
Mr. Kurapika demonstrated
that he’s incredibly knowledgeable.
Therefore, he passes.
-[Kurapika sighs in relief]
-Way to go, Kurapika.
Thanks.
-[son] Mr. Leorio?
-Yes?
You, sir, unfortunately never realized
that I wasn’t who I claimed to be.
[gulps]
[son] However, you dressed my wounds
faster and more thoroughly
than any doctor.
More importantly,
you demonstrated admirable empathy
and kindness
by continuing to reassure me
that my wife would be okay.
-[Gon and Kurapika chuckling]
-Knock it off, okay? It's embarrassing.
[son] It’s clear to me
that your compassion makes you worthy
of taking the Hunter Exam.
And so, you pass.
Wait, seriously? [sighs in relief]
You did it!
[both chuckle]
-[Kurapika 1] And finally, Mr. Gon.
-Yes?
Your superhuman physical ability
and your powers of observation defy logic.
You, too, are worthy
to take the Hunter Exam.
So, you pass.
[gasps]
[chuckles]
[Kurapika 1] Alright! We’ll now take you
straight to the site of the Exam!
Oh, wow! Isn’t it incredible
that we all passed?
[Kurapika] I wouldn't celebrate just yet.
We’ve merely earned the right
to take the Exam.
[Leorio] It's progress!
I say that calls for a little celebration!
[Kurapika] Honestly, have some foresight.
Do you have to be such a smartass
all the time-- [yells]
[Kurapika 2] Hey, stop squirming!
If you fall, it's your own fault.
[laughing]
[narrator] And so, Gon and his friends
enjoy a brief journey through the sky.
However, even after all this,
they have yet to reach the starting line.
[theme song playing]
[Gon] Next time! "Rivals in Survival."
I'm gonna do my best!